focus
innovate
enable
ics hair lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards honoring
the new age risk management
practitioners
good evening ladies and gentlemen and
welcome to the 8th edition of the icici
lombard general insurance and cnbc tv 18
presents india risk management awards
for almost half a decade india risk
management awards have been at the
forefront of celebrating excellence in
risk mitigation and this year we have
the uncertainties of the past behind and
make headway into the new normal the
kovit 19 crisis restricted us to our
homes for almost two years and today we
are in a room finally together face to
face leaving our zoom screens at home
and celebrating best risk management
teams and initiatives that are
innovative part breaking and those that
manage to build a strong foundation for
risk management in the country this
evening is about recognizing and
felicitating the risk managers of today
and tomorrow who safeguarded their
organizations against all odds and now
to set the tone for the evening i would
like to invite cnbc tv 18's executive
editor lata venkatesh to deliver a
welcome address
the india risk management awards which
we are doing with the support of icsi
lombard is by far one of the most
important and i would say rigorous event
that cnbc conducts and hosts the risk
management awards is the one that has
the most rigorous homework done by pwc
it has months and weeks of analysis of
what companies do
by way of managing their risk and then
the eminent jury is presented with the
data and the
jury also goes through you know
sometimes half a day sometimes a whole
day of analysis of that data so i must
tell you that this set of awards and
winners whom you are
seeing
are people who have been judged by very
very demanding standards and for that
count alone my warmest congratulations
to all of you who are here
this is the eighth edition and i'm very
happy to tell you that with each passing
year these awards have gone from
strength to strength this year we had in
spite of remote virtual analysis and
presentation we had the largest number
of nominations 550 companies putting
their hands up for various awards and
sub-award categories
important part of this award is we are
not trying to say that all these
companies or india as a corporate
culture has arrived in terms of risk
management but it is certainly an effort
to try and ferret out the best among
indian corporate sector as well as
propagate the idea with each passing
year we have more participants and so we
hope we have succeeded in pushing the
envelope and
encouraging more companies to think on
the lines of risk management as an
important element in their corporate
planning i wish you all a very happy
evening a very enriching evening thank
you very much for your patience
[Music]
thank you lata for setting the tone for
the evening and now to take us through
the journey of india risk management
awards i'd like to invite mr bhargavdas
gupta manager director and ceo icici
lombard general insurance for his
keynote address
[Applause]
you know the india risk management award
is
now about in its eighth year and this
year i think it's very special because
uh it recognizes individuals and
organizations and teams
uh who have had to
handle this
worldwide crisis that we've gone through
and come out so so strongly to be uh
to be considered and awarded you know
today so let's just put a round of
applause for all of you follow the
winners today
now at ics and lombard uh you know we
you've probably heard me say this many
times but
for us the context has been that you
know over the last eight nine years
we've tried to transform from being just
an insurance provider a company which
you know is your risk transfer partner
to your risk management uh you know
partner
and uh over the years what we've done is
add a lot of capabilities in terms of
providing risk advisory solutions using
data claims you know claims data
analytic analytics
and some of the new generation
technology tools like iot et cetera to
uh provide you with
uh
inputs and advice on risk management and
that's something that we are very happy
today that you know more than 3000
organizations across india use some of
these services from us
the other thing that we've always done
and we wanted to do all this all this
time has been uh focused on advocacy uh
you know our belief has been our
experience has been that there are many
many awards there are ceos of the years
cfo of the year but there's never been a
cro of the year which is so important
and advocacy to me is
an important and recognition advocacy
both are very very important
roles that we play as as isis lombard
now in that context one of the other
things that we are doing beyond you know
these events uh is the launch of a
corporate risk index and again you know
i'm very happy that we partnered with uh
frausence soliver who's our intellectual
partner in this
now this is a index that we launched
last year
we felt that there was no individual
unique matrix through which you could
measure your risk and based on feedback
we've actually now improved upon it and
this year second year of corporate you
know risk index
as i said supported by our intelligence
partner frost and silver
this index last year was very well
received by the corporate sector they
were very intrigued interested but we
obviously have to do a lot more work in
terms of evangelizing and getting them
to understand the benefits there's been
some changes as i said based on feedback
based on some of the changes in the in
the risk dynamics that we are seeing and
based on some of the recommendations
we've also expanded the coverage to five
more industries and today we will also
launch uh you know the second your
corporate risk index uh i don't want to
take the thunder that's for rook to
share with you and he'll come up and
talk about that index in due course so
with that i just want to uh again
congratulate all the winners
uh this is a tremendous achievement uh
you know really uh you know kudos to you
for
navigating these difficult times and
coming out winners in in this uh in in
the game of risk management
uh you've implemented
cutting-ed package practices and you've
demonstrated your skill in uh you know
being you know uh identified as leaders
in this in this sector thank you and
enjoy the evening and all the best
a big thank you mr daas gupta for those
insightful words but if i may request
you to kindly unveil the corporate risk
indian debt a huge chant of applause
for mr arup gucci as well
[Music]
icier lombard corporate india risk index
thank you for the honors
we are now invite mr arugushi global
president and managing partner frost and
sullivan on the stage to shed more light
on the corporate india risk index put
your hands together ladies and gentlemen
for mister
what you see here are six dimensions and
32 risk elements that are covered for
building this index
the six dimensions are obviously
emerging risks you heard about
operational and physical risk elements
you look at crime and security cyber
security in particular today is very
very important now what we are trying to
do here
is evaluate the risk exposure
which is basically a function of two
elements number one being awareness
everybody needs to be aware of what
those risks are in your business and
number two is the probability of that
risk hitting you and today we know with
so many external changes happening
the risk to every business is a lot
greater than what it used to be about a
decade ago the next one is a function of
risk management which is criticality and
the other is of course preparedness how
well are you prepared to respond to a
potential risk so these are the two
functions of course when you look at the
company risk index it's a function of
both the corporate risk exposure as well
as the risk management and it's the
combination of that too that gives you
what the corporate risk index is
now what do you do from here
as organizations how can you make sure
that you continue to improve
reduce the risk on your business
knowing very well that those risk
exposures will happen all the time i
think the first and foremost is
to have a dedicated team that drives
this agenda in your organizations
the second thing we recommend is global
i think you need to have a global view
on your business because the reality is
every business every part of the world
is being exposed to global mega trends
so what's happening in other parts of
the world is coming and happening in
this part of the world as well so having
a global view is very very important and
last but not least i would say
predictive and analytics and that is to
create scenarios look at data so you can
begin to predict what these risks might
be and what you can do to mitigate
reduce and preferably eliminate this
risk so as corporates as you continue to
build your growth story your growth
plans please keep this in mind as as you
as you go to the next level in your
organization's story as well so with
that thank you once again
ici hair lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards honoring
the new age risk management
practitioners good evening everybody
it's my great pleasure to be here let me
pick up four themes so the first thing i
want to pick up is on social media
social media has increased brand
reputation risk and corporate reputation
risk tremendously because today instead
of that central control you have a
democratization
of pr you know every person who has a
social media account whether they are
your employee their your customer or not
your customer can impact your brand and
so this has become a very big challenge
how do we get social listening and of
course to have the five people in the
headquarters listening or across all
social media is just not something that
will give us the coverage we need so
what we need to do is we need to use all
our employees as a tool in the sense of
figuring out who is doing what about our
thing and the other thing is to use our
employees because nobody is more
credible
in social media talking about your brand
than your employees especially if they
say something negative you know so we
have to be very careful of what our
employees are saying on online and what
they are saying in the different social
media for and so companies like
microsoft with microsoft life or
marriott with marriott careers or my
henkel are trying to set up
social media accounts which will help
the employees
tell the story of the company as cisco
said instead of you know
tweeting like a 70 000 person company
can't we tweet like 70 000 people
working for a company you know because
we want to retweet our employees and
make them more efficient ambassadors of
ours the second point i want to make
that risk management in the end is about
managing a process right it's about
integrity of process and people
following processes the problem in india
sometimes we have is we think of
ourselves as individuals and creative so
we always think that the process applies
to other people not to me personally you
know and i'll give you an example i was
with a friend of mine who owns one of
the top leading hotels in delhi and the
terrorist attack had taken place in in
delhi and he was i was driving with him
to the hotel and he was telling me of
all the new processes they put in place
in terms of keeping this hotel safe
and it was very impressive then we
reached the gate of the hotel where
everybody is supposed to be checked the
moment they saw it was the owner of the
car he was checked and he was elected
right so i told him i said you know
instead of all the processes you put in
place had you just stopped the card at
that stage and fired the guy who didn't
check you that would have been more
effective in terms of risk management
you know but you know but the thing is
what i'm trying to say is the deference
to a hierarchy is not good for risk
management and not only in india
globally we know more accidents more
plane
crashes take place when the head chief
pilot is on the controls then when the
assistant pilot is on control because
when the assistant pilot is on control
if something is going wrong the chief
pilot will immediately intervene but
when the chief pilot is on the controls
and something is going wrong the
assistant pilot hesitates because of
hierarchy the third thing i want to say
is which was mentioned earlier is about
these new business models that are
coming up you see large incumbent firms
are very good at risk management as was
mentioned by the previous speaker
group because they have good processes
in place to recognize
and mitigate risk
and it's because of these processes they
are able to scale up businesses rapidly
and relentlessly
but the problem is this works really
really well in stable certain
environments when the environment is
quickly changing or when things are
uncertain these same processes get in
the way of flexibility and change
so
incumbent companies excellent at
exploitation of existing opportunities
but poor at exploration when the
environment is changing and that is the
risk that they face the biggest risk for
existing companies is disruption
business model disruption risk startups
are different they don't manage risk
through processes they don't have the
processes they manage risk through
flexibility and pivoting
they keep pivoting keep pivoting until
they perfect the business model until
they find the opportunity where they can
make a difference that's how they but
what they fear so they're very good at
exploration but they're very poor at
exploitation their biggest risk is they
won't be able to scale up
and they face existential risk the risk
that i won't be in business tomorrow so
it's different kind of risk for for the
large corporates versus the small
corporates and in risk management is
very important to understand that the
cure cannot be worse
than the problem
and then the last thing with which i
will close
one of the things we tell companies
today is don't keep too much cash right
because you know that's a sign of are
you trying to be a bank right return it
as dividends do stock buybacks whatever
it is right but don't keep the slack of
cash the second thing we tell companies
is these conglomerates don't make any
sense to us because they do many things
none of them really well without any
shared infrastructure to get synergies
right so we there's a lot of active
shareholders who basically tell
companies return the cash and if you are
a diversified conglomerate group break
it up and make focused companies instead
right it turns out that the covett
pandemic makes me made me reflect on
what is it that makes a company
resilient to such blacks on events and
it may be that the presence of slack and
loose coupling is what allows you to
survive this kind of black swan events
so
you know first with respect to slack
you know what is slack slack is a sign
of inefficiency in good times but in bad
times this is the fact
that allows bears
to survive the harsh winter
right it is this slack that gives you
that resilience to survive when things
go completely haywired of course
in terms of good times it looks like an
efficiency and of course all slack is
not
you know resilience right so we have to
be careful but all slack in good times
if you don't expect an anticipated event
will look like inefficiency right the
second thing is loose coupling you know
what is loose coupling loose coupling
says in a complex system i can take a
hit on one
part of my system and not have the
entire system collapse and this was a
truth that was pointed out by herb simon
who won the nobel prize 50 years ago and
he used a parable about two watchmakers
hora and tempus tempest made all his
watches in one continuous process
hoda made it by doing sub assemblies and
putting them together
when an unexpected event happened which
made them lose all their work
tempest lost the entire watch hola lost
just one sub-assembly what i'm trying to
say is that
the lesson is that systems composed of
weakly com weakly coupled parts can take
a hit in one part without the entire
system coming crashing down right
but of course in good time this loose
coupling looks like missed opportunities
for optimization
and you know efficiency through enhanced
coordination so thank you very much i
hope this gave you some ideas to think
about and i look forward to the rest of
the evening
[Applause]
thank you mr kumar i'm sure everybody in
this room has benefited from your
enlightening and enriching speech moving
on to an exciting fireside chat on how
to master risk management strategies and
tactics companies need to deliberate and
a lot more over to you lata
talent risk that's emerged again at all
levels and definitely at the top because
of the increased number of startups and
the lack of talent that
pool at that level where the talent risk
is now with is that the younger
generation is very different in their
hopes and aspirations than the past and
the younger generation the millennials
you know they basically
a couple of things over there first
thing is that you know
the way you
they want companies
to take political stands they want
companies to be actively engaged in
social activism and this is very
different from the older generation
which felt that companies should be in
the business of running business and
leave this
other stuff to governments to recall but
as disney has just found out facebook
has found out google has found out you
cannot
move yourself away from the social
dilemmas that
the world is facing because your younger
employees will say how can i work for
you anymore that's the first thing
secondly in terms of attraction
motivation and compensation and all
these things
the in the old days
when the young person came to you they
wanted to know what is the career path
in this company how am i going to have a
job for life and how are you going to
move me across this organization right
today
people are not interested in that they
want to know how are you going to invest
in me what experiences are you going to
give me that will make me more mobile
instead of giving me a job for a life
this job should make me more mobile for
life
and so that is a very big difference you
know and we are still
struggling in terms of how do we you
know keep these people motivated and
with us and what motivates them more
than compensation sometimes though
because they said we'll always get the
compensation is the values of the
company the way you treat them and that
is why microsoft has changed their
attraction of hr and the attraction of
young people from they used to have this
tagline empower your future with
microsoft now it is come as you are do
what you love
cyber risk
i mean uh time was when most of the
financial companies like yourselves and
probably big companies like htfc bank
and sbi housed all the servers with
themselves now you are out there with
apps and you know the easiest app is the
one that the well you're the customer
but that also is most prone to cyber
escaping the more we use our uh upi
probably uh our or our aadhaar uh you
know or the more we use perhaps an
amazon pay google pay we are at risk of
giving away our numbers somewhere and uh
how do you guys handle this
well i think that's a that's one of the
toughest things to you know
to handle honestly speaking so if you
look at you know we just talked about
the digitization and the disruption that
it is bringing about i think what it's
also doing is increasing the cyber risk
right and i think the last two years
because of the pandemic work from home
it's clearly gone you all may have had
to share a lot of your data to uh you
know yeah so so i'm coming to that so if
you look at the overall number of cyber
attacks it's not just about data sharing
it's about the uh the uh cyber attacks
that we are facing so if you look at the
21 numbers and over 20 we had a
four times increase in the cyber attacks
in this country and you know numbers
going into millions of cases we had 4
000 per person increase in phishing
emails now how do you prepare for you
for that as an organization you may have
your you know cyber risk management you
know processes you have your protocols
you have your governance uh you know as
you know standards you have to do all of
that and you hope at the end of the day
it works
uh you know and we say you know we do
all of this every day we have review
mechani not every day but we have a
monitoring mechanism we have uh you know
threat identification tools we have uh
uh threat mitigation you know practices
uh threat hunting you know services
provided by external players who are
looking at threat hunting so but at the
end of the day all of this is kind of we
are still hoping at the end of the day
and in the morning you're waking up and
hoping that all of this is going to work
and nothing's going to happen to you
because if you look at some of the
surveys
we believe that
more than 60 of indian companies had a
ransomware attack last year
and i'm sure all of them are doing
something to prevent this right so it's
it's a it's a real uh concern any case
finally you have a cyber insurance from
us that's the only thing that you can
open the best thing would be to keep the
insurance that's not be attacked
are you
in this uh have you been consulted on
this issue at all i would say that
customer education is also a very
important part we have not educated our
people not to what apps to download what
apps not to download what information to
give and not give this is a very big
deficit most people
they have a mobile phone but they don't
know what are the dangers to this and
i'll add employee education i think the
constant awareness and education for to
prevent employees from you know by by
mistake clicking a phishing email right
everything that you've done just because
of one error everything can be
compromised thank you very much
for the second treat thank you thank you
so much
ici hair lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards honoring
the new age risk management
practitioners
good evening ladies and gentlemen and
welcome to the 8th edition of the icici
lombard general insurance and cnbc tv 18
presents india risk management awards
well in its 8th edition the risk
management awards recognizes those
organizations and teams that have
significantly added to the understanding
and practice of risk management in this
edition we feature all three the large
mid and small cap segments along with
our knowledge partner we have
meticulously put together which is of
course price worker house cooper's 20
plus award categories across the large
and mid cap segments we've received a
lot of nomination from across various
sectors and the jury carefully contended
and deliberated the final list of with
us a jury consisted of india inc's
biggest experts like shailesh hari
bhakti chairman hari bhakti and company
ramesh swaminathan cfo and head of
corporate affairs lupin sandeep batra
cfo crompton grieves consumer
electricals bhaskaran rao cfo bengaluru
international airport harsha ceo irm
india affiliate shruti kanan head cisco
launchpad sandeep naga director nimsme
ministry of msme sumit gupta cro yes
bank avantika gold managing director
vice funding india and himanshuwas
president and business head bank finance
at kotak mahindra bank i would like to
thank our jury members who had a
daunting task of selecting winners
across different categories now to
present the award may i invite on stage
our chief guest mr nirmala kumar mr
bharg of dasgupta and lata venkatesh
[Applause]
our first set of awards this evening are
for the mid and small cap segments risk
management has taken a front stage
during the pandemic and good risk
management means being alert and
mitigating risk even in a crisis
situation our first category this
evening is masters of risk conglomerate
and the award goes to
the lohia group
[Music]
[Applause]
moving on to our next award category
which is masters of risk private sector
and the winner in this category is tata
realty and infrastructure
[Applause]
moving on the healthcare sector was at
the forefront while battling the covet
19 crisis analyzing mitigating and
calculating risk are an everyday chore
for the health care sector our next
category for the evening is masters of
risk health care sector and the winner
is dr lal park
[Applause]
let's swiftly move on to the next
category this evening which is the
masters of risk hospitality sector we've
got two winners in the same category and
in no particular order let me announce
the first winner and which is mahindra
holidays and resorts
[Applause]
and let's see who else mitigated risks
and carefully in the hospitality sector
and the winner is hilton hotels
management india
[Applause]
[Music]
moving on to our next category which is
masters of risk manufacturing sector and
the winner in this category is
ladies and gentlemen please put your
hands together for victoria otto
[Applause]
[Music]
on to the next category of the india
risk management awards 2022 which is
masters of risk in real estate and the
award goes to tata realty and
infrastructure
[Music]
[Applause]
moving on due to the pandemic the retail
and consumer sector has witnessed
multiple changes and disruptions they've
had to reimagine their business model
and prepare for the upcoming risk our
next category for this evening is
masters of risk retail and consumer
sector and the winner is wemart retail
[Applause]
our next recognition is from the
category masters of risk and business
continuity planning and the award goes
to visa consolidated support services
[Applause]
cyber security issues are becoming more
alarming and cyber crime has surged
during the covert 19 pandemic in fact
india saw three times more cyber attacks
in 2020 than in 2019. the next category
is cyber security and the winner is gati
kintetsu express
[Applause]
[Music]
our next category is masters of risk in
business model adaptability let's see
who the jury thought was worthy of the
title and the award goes to a vendor's
capital
[Applause]
moving on to our next category which is
masters of risk in risk technology let's
see who had the acumen to tranquilize
risk ladies and gentlemen please welcome
on stage once again visa consolidated
support services
[Applause]
[Music]
on to another award this evening our
next category is masters of risk in
regulatory compliance we've got two
winners from this category two and the
first award goes to tata realty and
infrastructure
[Applause]
the second award from the same category
goes to zomato
[Applause]
next category in the india risk
management awards is masters of risk in
fraud prevention and ethics management
and bagging another award this evening
is zamato so please come back on stage
[Applause]
[Music]
the next category is masters of risk in
risk governance and the award goes to
well once again visa consolidated
support services
[Applause]
[Music]
moving on our next award category is
masters of risk private sector and the
award goes to vista financial services
[Applause]
the next category from the mid cap
segment is masters of risk manufacturing
sector ladies and gentlemen please put
your hands together for satan's sons
[Applause]
next up we have a special jewelry
citation for risk management in the
startup sector and the special mention
goes to skylar global bpo service
[Applause]
[Music]
ici hair lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards honoring
the new age risk management
practitioners we now move on to the
large cap category awards the first
category in the large cap segment is
masters of risk private sector and the
award goes to tata power company
[Applause]
moving on our second award in the large
cap segment is masters of risk psu
sector ladies and gentlemen please put
your hands together for ongc vidish
[Applause]
our next category this evening is
masters of risk auto ancillary sector
and the winner in this category is
apollo tires
[Applause]
our next category ladies and gentlemen
is masters of risk automotive oem let's
see which company stood out for our
jewelry and the award goes to ashok
leyland
[Applause]
[Music]
the fmcg was the hardest hit during the
pandemic but as we see customers gaining
confidence fmcg is witnessing high
growth figures and our next category
this evening is masters of risk fmcg
sector and the winner is tata consumer
products
[Applause]
moving on to the next category masters
of risk hospitality sector please put
your hands together for thomas cook
india
[Applause]
i would now like to move on to the next
recognition this evening the special
jury citation for risk management in
hospitality sector and the special
citation goes to the indian hotels
company
[Applause]
moving on to the next category for this
evening masters of risk itites
we again have two winners in this
category and the first award goes to jen
pact
[Applause]
and the second award in the masters of
risk ites sector goes to tata
consultancy services
[Applause]
[Music]
and our next category is masters of risk
metals and mining please put your hands
together for the winner tata steel
[Applause]
our next category ladies and gentlemen
for the evening is masters of risk
pharma sector and the award goes to
glaxosmithkline pharmaceuticals
[Applause]
[Music]
our next category at the india risk
management awards is masters of risk
power sector and the winner is
tata power company
[Applause]
[Music]
moving on to the recognition in the
finance sector the most critical one
when it comes to managing risk masters
of risk banking and nbfc sector and the
award goes to tata capital
[Applause]
moving on to our next category which is
masters of risk telecom sector and the
award goes to reliance geo infocom
[Applause]
our next category is masters of risk in
business continuity planning ladies and
gentlemen please put your hands together
once again for genpak
[Applause]
our next recognition is from the
category masters of risk in cyber
security and the winner is
tata consultancy services
[Applause]
our next category this evening is
masters of risk in regulatory compliance
and the winner in this category is tata
consultancy services
[Applause]
[Music]
our next category this evening is
masters of risk in risk technology and
the winner is ongc videsh
[Applause]
our next category is masters of risk in
fraud prevention and ethics management
ladies and gentlemen please put your
hands together once again for the tata
power company
[Applause]
our next category is masters of risk in
fraud prevention and ethics management
and the winner is hindustan zing
[Applause]
our next recognition this evening is a
special jury citation in fraud
prevention and ethics management and the
citation award goes to maricopa
[Applause]
our next category is masters of risk in
risk governance and the award goes to
genpak
[Applause]
we now turn our focus to risk management
in the supply chain sector and the
winner is please put your hands together
for nestle india
[Applause]
moving on to our next recognition which
is a special jewry citation for supply
chain risk management and the citation
goes to all cargo logistics
[Applause]
our next category ladies and gentlemen
is masters of risk in brand and social
media risk management and the award goes
to the indian hotels company limited
[Applause]
our second last category for the evening
is masters of risk in environmental
social and governance and the award goes
to marico
[Applause]
ladies and gentlemen that brings us to
the last award of the evening the
masters of risk in business model
adaptability and the award goes to the
indian hotels company limited
[Applause]
a big congratulations to all the winners
this evening it's a wrap of the india
risk management awards 2022 a big thanks
to our jury members who did the toughest
job of choosing the winners for this
year on behalf of cnbc tv 18 i'd also
like to thank our presenting sponsor
icici lombard for making this edition of
the india risk management awards a
successful one
ici hair lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards honoring
the new age risk management
practitioners
[Music]
focus
ideal
innovate
enable